hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is Jeremy
Krakowski and on this podcast I help
coaches trainers mentors and thought
leaders scale their businesses and make
six seven and even eight Figures it's
over 10 million dollars online that's
the track record of what we've created
for coaches mentors trainers and thought
leaders in the online space and I want
to help you get there as well now today
I am on my treadmill right now because
this is where I find the most
inspiration currently in my life and so
if you hear a little bit of the
treadmill background noise I do
apologize for that but hopefully the
iPhone should be able to pick this up
pretty well those of you wondering kind
of how I recorded this I just press
record right on my own my iPhone I'm
here in my garage right here and we're
recording the podcast episode like this
you know I'm really inspired to share
something with you that I think is going
to help you
it's this it's this level that I think
that we have to cross over if we want to
be successful as a coach as a mentor as
a trainer online that you know I notice
a lot of people are really hesitant to
cross over into and it separates those
that are financially successful from
those that aren't okay you have to
become free from other people's opinions
about you okay I just did a presentation
this week this weekend and I had a
person on the presentation tell me that
my methods that I teach which if you
listen to my podcast if you join my
trainings you know what I teach you know
that it's effective that it works
and she said
that what I teach is disrespectful and
rude to other people now this got me
thinking like wait a sec is it
disrespectful right I have empathy I
want to look internally see is there
something I can learn here from this and
at the end of the day I realized no
actually this lady as you know as much
as I want to honor her for her own
unique individual perspective
I completely disagree with her her her
her her thought process on this to the
point that like
if she thinks
bad things about me because of that I am
okay with that and I do not need to
prove myself I do not need to defend
myself I do not need to create some kind
of campaign or narrative to prove that
what I say is right and she's wrong I
don't need to fight this I don't even
need to go so deep into Judgment of what
she's saying and what what I found is is
that
the perspective was is this is that if
you send too many emails to somebody
and it wastes their time that you're
harming that person and you're rude and
disrespectful and I disagree I send
emails twice a day to my email list
it actually got me to the point where I
was almost afraid to send emails to my
list over the past 24 hours
like like me who sends emails
consistently has a consistent business
that makes multiple six figures
has a track record of two decades
and then the opinion of one person got
me to almost completely change the
behavior of my business out of fear and
worry of what this person thought now
obviously I snapped out of it but this
goes to show you that even somebody like
myself who's been in this for this long
I am susceptible to opinions thoughts
and things that other people say
and I I'm just gonna be real vulnerable
with y'all I am actually very guilty of
this over the last couple years I have
made decisions in my business a couple
years ago
that were not healthy profitable
decisions for my business because
somebody made a comment to me that
triggered me and I went completely 180
doing behavior that would not produce
success in my business
I had somebody write me the other day
tell me that I I post too much on my
social media and then I need to stop or
they're going to hurt me
okay like am I gonna stop doing that no
I'm not afraid of that person and you
have to give up the fear and worry of
what other people think about you or
even what they're going to do and this
this catastrophizing of what people
might do to you that will stop you from
being successful I've talked with a
handful of my clients in our coaching
group
they won't launch an offer out there
because they are afraid of disappointing
other people
if they don't quote unquote get the
result that they promised and then that
person coming after them and physically
attacking them
because of their disappointment okay
and so like this
fear of people's opinions and what
people will do to us
and changing our Behavior off of the
opinions of a public that's out there
and shifting our business decisions in a
direction that are unprofitable that
will not make money that will prevent us
from making money in order to appease a
very small percentage of the marketplace
that is unhealthy Behavior that is not a
healthy way to operate to think and to
live and that's a prison and it's a trap
and it's a trap that many people fall
into and it's a trap that many of us
have been groomed for and many of us
have been taught many of us have been
raised that way we might even be in
relationships right now with a friend or
a spouse
that is constantly telling us that we
need to worry about what other people
think here's here how did that come in
for me honestly it's how I grew up
some of you all know my story you know
my mom she's a fireball amazing Fearless
business woman she wasn't that way
growing up and she really imparted a lot
of fear in me about other people's
opinions as a child and my behavior as a
child I was raised to be terrified of
what anybody thought about us to always
worry about making the perception of our
family be perfect in order to protect
our family to protect different things
like that
[Laughter]
that behavior is not rooted in anything
that's healthy that behavior is not
rooted in anything
that will serve you to reach your goals
you know growing up we used to be afraid
that because my mom homeschooled me that
I that she would be taken to jail and so
we would shut the blinds during the day
to make sure that people neighbors going
by wouldn't see that we were
homeschooling inside of our house
now some of y'all might say well that's
wisdom
well that's you know that's being wise I
I there's a level of that
99.9 of the time though that's it's not
wisdom and it's not coming from a wise
waste it's coming from a place of
letting fear run you
letting the worry of what people might
think run you I saw I met somebody
um six months ago she refused to spend
three hundred dollars out of her nine
million dollar portfolio out of fear
that if she lost that 300 that she would
be judged as a bad investor by her
friends
and so she refused to test something out
in her business out of fear of appearing
incompetent to others and how they would
judge her and how they would come after
her and what they would say and so
here's the thing we have to develop
thick skin
we have to grow to a place where we do
not make our decisions in our business
based off of what other people might
think might say what that and we might
not we don't have to agree with it
like they could be so off base
we don't have to defend ourselves we
don't have to protect ourselves we don't
have to make sure to make sure that they
don't do the thing that we don't want
them to do right this person who came to
me on my call
it's not my job I don't need to make
sure that people like that don't show up
on my call they're going to show up
it's part of the territory that we're in
I don't need to make sure that I please
everybody who becomes a customer
customer of mine I don't need to make
sure that every single person
likes me
and approves of me
but that's what our that's what our
society tells us it tries to convince us
that we have to be worried about how
we're perceived by others
what people think about us we have to
manage our reputation hardcore to make
sure that nobody thinks anything ill of
us I'm sorry but that's a load of crap
I don't buy it and in my experience in
the last two decades it does not help
you especially in the coaching mentoring
thought leading space to be successful
it's Kryptonite it's one of the number
one things that will keep you from
making the kind of money that you want
to make and I stand by this so firmly is
that we have to divorce
being concerned about other people's
opinions about our actions in business
not everybody's going to agree with you
not everybody is going to buy into your
standards I've had people attack me for
numerous things I don't need to go into
it I just scratched the surface today
okay I'll talk about one of them I had
somebody get so angry that I said that
you don't need to invest in massive
Graphics design in your business in
order to be successful and turns out he
was a graphics designer and he felt that
I was destroying his industry and was a
threat to him and his family and he
started to come after me physically and
start and and and threatened to hurt me
if I didn't stop talking about this the
way that I did I just blocked him on
social media like that you got to
realize the people who are doing that
are not healthy mentally okay they're
getting some kind of validation
by scaring other people
they're getting some kind of validation
by threatening other people
okay now I want to share this with you
you know back in the day when I felt
like I was a powerless person I used to
make
verbal not not threats but I would say
things that would scare people because I
felt powerless and so I have empathy for
this and as I've grown to realize that
I'm not a powerless person that I'm not
just sitting in a boat and life is
passing me by that I am actually the
master commander and and I am steering
the ship in my life that other people
are not steering the ship in my life
once I realized that
I no longer felt the need
to say things if I felt threatened by
other people to make them back off or do
things
and so when somebody does that when
somebody comes to you in business
and they say something that's scary
it's because they feel powerless
it's because they feel that you have
something over them and that if they can
stop you then they've won and protected
themselves that's the only reason why
people do that and so I want to
encourage you in this you do not have to
protect yourself
from attackers and people coming after
you and trying to protect yourself from
the opinions of people that are out
there on the internet when you run your
offers when you put your offers out
there you're gonna get a wide range of
feedback from people not everybody's
going to like it not everybody's going
to agree with you you could do all the
right things and still have very
negative Rude mean and even threatening
people come after you out of the
woodwork
it's not your job to protect yourself
and prevent that from happening
and it's also part of the business of
coaching mentoring training and being a
thought leader it is you're not going to
be able to avoid it
and so to this person who has told me
that I am rude and disrespectful for
what I'm saying and and that I you know
whatever
story that she's made up
I fully like she can think whatever she
wants about me I don't need to prove
myself I disagree but that's where it
ends I don't need to validate my
position
to anybody
I don't need to bring people over to my
side in order to feel safe I don't need
people to agree with me
in order for my business to thrive
and oftentimes what we really do is we
shrink ourselves down to the level of
other people's judgment
we shrink ourselves down to the level of
what other people have told us
that they don't like us Crossing that
line and then when we operate inside of
coloring inside of the lines of other
people's opinions
it becomes nearly impossible to make a
profit in our business why is that
because business is about taking risks
business is about pushing the envelope
business is about doing the things that
most people are terrified of doing why
are most people terrified of doing those
things in business because they're
afraid of other people because they're
afraid of it going wrong because they're
afraid of it not producing the result
they want so when you go out there in
your business and you're saying I'm
afraid of doing anything because I'm
afraid of not working out and I'm afraid
of it not producing the result that I
want and you literally stop yourself
from the very thing that will set you
free financially because you are afraid
you've let
everything else win and you have become
a victim in your life
to outside circumstances to outside
influences you'll become a victim in
your life to everything else
around you I dropped my phone
you become a victim to everything else
around you in your life
and you can change that with one
decision most people never will most
people never do most people will go
through the motions of victim blame
scarcity lack mentality and then they'll
get a little bit of an inspiration
they'll they'll hear a podcast or
they'll they'll hear a preaching or
they'll go through a course and they'll
go through a training or they'll go
through a coaching program they'll feel
inspired and then they go back to their
real life and they get influenced by
their friends their family the news
media their social media and they shrink
themselves right back down to the little
tiny box of Their Fear
the little tiny box of I am terrified to
push the envelope I am terrified to even
do the very thing that I'm called to do
and it's a choice that you got to make
to not let those things control you
it's a choice that you got to make to
not let fear and worry and doubt and
other people's opinions stop you from
doing the very thing
that will move things forward for you in
your life and so if that means me
sending an email out twice a day and it
pissing off one percent of the people
who sign up on my email list and they're
just angry at me you know what I'm okay
with angering that one percent of people
they can unsubscribe not my job to
manage maintain or control how they feel
it's just not
not my job to make other people think
things about me that I agree with
my job is to focus on what can I do to
grow my business to impact people to
help those that love me that celebrate
me that are connected with me and to
connect with more of those people so
that I can bring impact into their lives
and that's why I'm here on this podcast
that's why I'm here on this treadmill
today that's why I'm here talking to you
about this so passionately that's why I
don't stay silent on this
because I care about it
and I know that when you get this and
you start to apply this in your life and
your actions follow and you do something
the first time that you make a decision
to do something that goes against what
everybody else around you is telling you
to do and you even have people telling
you stop or I will stop you see that's
crazy and that's an experience that you
may have to reach
where people will literally tell you I
had a lady tell me
four years ago Jeremiah it is my mission
to make sure that you never succeed at
coaching and I will do everything I can
to make sure you never do
and I blocked her on social media and
her friends came after me and I blocked
her friends on social media and guess
what they didn't stop me and they can't
stop me and the people who threaten you
won't be able to stop you you cannot let
other people's opinions stop you from
reaching your goals wanna know why she
told me that she was going to stop me
from doing that
it was the very thing that I'm actually
teaching you here today
is the very thing I'm actually teaching
you here today she told me that this
message that I'm teaching you of not
being afraid of other people's opinions
was too dangerous for the world to hear
in public
that it was too threatening to society
and that if my message that I'm teaching
you today got out it would do too much
harm to the world as a whole and guess
what I'm still here today teaching it
I'm still here today sharing it publicly
boldly not holding back because I know
that it'll change your life like it has
mine and I'm excited for those who grab
onto this who really have ears to hear
who really start to apply this in their
lives you're going to see breakthrough
grow your life everybody we'll talk soon
have a good one
[Music]
thank you